SAIF AL-MUSAWI

Phone: +61 420657829 • Email: saifalmusawi1308@gmail.com • LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/saif-almusawi-1308

Career Profile

Graduate of both the Batchelor of Biomedical Science and the Bachelor of Health and Medical Science (Honours) at Deakin University and a current 4th Year Pharmacy Student at Monash University. Have 4 years of qualitative and quantitative research skills, including data analysis, literature reviews, participant recruitment, wireframing/designing a blueprint on methodology and extracting data. Collaborated with project supervisors to complete the project and to the stakeholders needs. Have experience in building and collaborating with app developers to create programs for the project in VR. Looking to work in a Health or Science related field and in Research too.

Education

Bachelor of Pharmacy (Honours) and Masters of Pharmacy MONASH UNIVERSITY, Parkville, Victoria

November 2021 - Present

• Graduate Entry Student commencing study in January 2022

Bachelor of Health and Medical Science (Honours) DEAKIN UNIVERSITY, Waurn Ponds, Victoria

February 2021 - November 2021

- Completed course, graduated with Second Class Honours Division A (H2A).
- Worked with Project Supervisors on how 'changes in motion perception are perceived with a change in stereopsis (binocular depth perception).'
- Completed prior literature review and writing a thesis and presented findings to the rest of the 2022 cohort.
- Used SPSS for Data Analysis, including doing data cleaning, analysis and interpretation.
- Collaborated with Developers to build an application in VR, following up with basis and refining design and interaction to be ready for use for participants/users.
- Also completed Graduate Medical Admissions test in February 2021, achieved an overall score of 62.

Bachelor of Biomedical Science DEAKIN UNIVERSITY, Burwood, Victoria

January 2018 - December 2020

- Achieving High Distinction, GPA of 6.64.
- Completed a complementary Research Placement with Project Managers for 16 weeks, cleaning qualitative data and using visual charts to define the findings.
- Also completed units undertaking multiple data analytics and used R for statistics.
- Used understanding and empathy for stakeholders by defining what teachers think works best for students consistent interest and performance in chemistry from three different countries: Australia, Estonia and Slovenia.
- With the findings, insights were made to oversee what further research had to be done to increase the knowledge in the field and to help teachers understand over an international demographic what is most effective in teaching their students.
- Applied for the Graduate Medical Admissions test during March and September 2019, achieving an overall score of 57.

Experience

ONLINE SCIENCE EDUCATION PROJECT RESEARCHER Deakin University 221 Burwood Hwy, Burwood, VIC 3125

July 2020 - October 2020

- Undertaking a work placement on a weekly, under the School of Life and Environmental Sciences at Deakin, to present a project aimed to better understand impact of chemistry demonstrations on students studying chemistry and other science subjects.
- Contacting supervisor's fortnightly to discuss any progress made between each meeting and making revisions to each draft of project, before due for publishing in 16th week of placement.
- Presented project to both scientific and teaching community on how demonstrations impacted students learning due to teachers' examples and lead in 3 countries: Australia, Estonia and Slovenia.

STUDENT PHARMACIST

Chemist Warehouse, 6/420 Princes Hwy, Narre Warren, VIC 3805

April 2022 - Present

- Working as a Student Pharmacist at Chemist Warehouse Fountain Gate to collect prescriptions and gather patient information.
- Collecting medication, dispensing, and counselling patients with medications.
- Providing health advice and Over-The-Counter (OTC) solutions to customer queries.
- Offering external services to customers if it is a request that is not provided by the business.

Volunteer Experience

TREASURER

Deakin Science Society, Burwood, Victoria

November 2018 - September 2019

- Volunteered to become clubs founding Treasurer and allow it to be an established club of Deakin University.
- Conducted payments and reimbursements to multiple companies and facilities, so to pay for facilities and services within 1 week.
- Collaborated with other clubs, such as the Deakin Biomedical (DUBS) and Psychology Society (DUPS) to provide events to students, members and non-members alike.
- Organized grant forms to aid in paying for events such as weekly study sessions, mid and end of trimester party alongside the Hawthorn Hotel.
- Managed emails sent to and from members and companies regarding goods or upcoming events occurring 2-3 weeks ahead.

MENTOR

Peer Student Network, Deakin University, Burwood, Victoria

February 2019 - July 2019

- Volunteered as a Mentor for the Deakin Science, Engineering and Built Environment Faculty.
- Mentored first year students to manage around Deakin and to use facilities and services found on campus.
- Collaborated with another mentor to aid mentees and came to all meetings weekly.

Professional Membership

- Deakin University Student Association (DUSA), Membership status Member (2019/2020)
- Deakin Science Society, Membership status Member (2019/2020)

Additional Information

- Software skills: Microsoft Excel, R (Statistical Program), SPSS.
- Clinical experience working with participants/users of application to find results of study.
- Software skills: Microsoft Excel, R (Statistical Program), SPSS.
- Laboratory skills: Proficiency in Microbiological sterile techniques, certificate to work in PC2 laboratories.
- Languages: English (fluent), Arabic (fluent).
- Volunteer in local Iraqi community living in south-eastern Victoria to help set up cultural and religious events so to keep relations strong and to understand Iraqi culture.

Referees

Dr. AMANDA DOUGLASS

Unit Chair Lecturer in Optometry and Vision Science, Supervisor for Bachelor of Health and Medical Science (Honours), Deakin University

- 75 Pigdons Road Burwood, Waurn Ponds VIC 3216, Australia.
- Tel: +61 3 522 78565
- Email: amanda.douglass@deakin.edu.au

BA/Prof. LARRY ABEL

Associate Professor in Visual Function, Deakin University

- 75 Pigdons Road Burwood, Waurn Ponds VIC 3216, Australia.
- Tel: +61 3 522 73881
- Email: larry.abel@deakin.edu.au